<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>USTC Trapped Ions Group</title><link href="http://lqcc.ustc.edu.cn/qng/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://lqcc.ustc.edu.cn/qng/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://lqcc.ustc.edu.cn/qng/</id><updated>2018-05-02T10:20:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>通知</title><link href="http://lqcc.ustc.edu.cn/qng/note.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-05-02T10:20:00+08:00</published><updated>2018-05-02T10:20:00+08:00</updated><author><name>qng</name></author><id>tag:lqcc.ustc.edu.cn,2018-05-02:/qng/note.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1 id="tong-zhi"&gt;通知&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;gitlab服务端口更改为82&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;http://210.45.114.46:82
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1 id="tong-zhi"&gt;通知&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;gitlab服务端口更改为82&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;http://210.45.114.46:82
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>"An Ultraviolet Fiber Fabry–Pérot Cavity for Florescence Collection of Trapped Ions" is published</title><link href="http://lqcc.ustc.edu.cn/qng/an-ultraviolet-fiber-fabry-perot-cavity-for-florescence-collection-of-trapped-ions-is-published.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-22T10:20:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-01-22T10:20:00+08:00</updated><author><name>qng</name></author><id>tag:lqcc.ustc.edu.cn,2017-01-22:/qng/an-ultraviolet-fiber-fabry-perot-cavity-for-florescence-collection-of-trapped-ions-is-published.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We publish a technical work on fabericate fiber cavities for trapped ion.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We publish a technical work on fabericate fiber cavities for trapped ion.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>"Experimental Trapped-ion Quantum Simulation of the Kibble-Zurek dynamics in momentum space" is published</title><link href="http://lqcc.ustc.edu.cn/qng/experimental-trapped-ion-quantum-simulation-of-the-kibble-zurek-dynamics-in-momentum-space-is-published.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-22T10:20:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-09-22T10:20:00+08:00</updated><author><name>qng</name></author><id>tag:lqcc.ustc.edu.cn,2016-09-22:/qng/experimental-trapped-ion-quantum-simulation-of-the-kibble-zurek-dynamics-in-momentum-space-is-published.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We published a quantum simulation work on Scientific report as "Experimental Trapped-ion Quantum Simulation of the Kibble-Zurek dynamics in momentum space". This is the first experiment work on trapped ion in our group. We start to build the ion trap experiment in 2013, and many efforts have been done  build …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We published a quantum simulation work on Scientific report as "Experimental Trapped-ion Quantum Simulation of the Kibble-Zurek dynamics in momentum space". This is the first experiment work on trapped ion in our group. We start to build the ion trap experiment in 2013, and many efforts have been done  build the platform.  We would like to thank to our collaborators Le Luo and Adolf de Campo, who give us help on both experiment and theory.  Congratulations！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the article in this link : &lt;a href="http://www.nature.com/articles/srep33381"&gt;http://www.nature.com/articles/srep33381&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="about-the-work"&gt;About the work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study of nonequilibrium dynamics of quantum systems forms a vast field of research of relevance to a wide variety of disciplines ranging from cosmology to condensed matter, as well as quantum simulation and computation, to name just a few prominent examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure half left" style="max-width: 400px; min-width: 5.5em;"&gt;
&lt;img "="" ]"="" alt="[Image. Experimental setup" border="1" src="./images/news/scientific_report2016/SetUp.jpg" style="max-width: 400px; max-height: 310px;" title="Experimental setup"/&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt; Fig.1. Experimental setup using an ion-trap.  ( A ) Configuration of six needles of the trap used in experiment. (B) Yb+ energy spectrum: the hyperfine energy levels (|0&amp;gt; and |1&amp;gt;) of the ground state are used as the qubit. (C) Microwave control scheme of the driving field around 12.642 GHz: the frequency is generated by mixing microwaves between 9.64 GHz and 3 GHz, while 3 GHz microwave is IQ modulated by a dual channel AFG around 2 MHz. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;T. W. B. Kibble&amp;rsquo;s most cited contribution to science dates back to 1980 and ignited an explosion of interest in the field. He predicted in a cosmological setting that breaking of symmetry is governed by causality, and that topological defect formation is to be expected with the crossing of a continuous phase transition, which is ineluctably nonadiabatic. It was W. H. Zurek who refined these arguments soon after and turned the study of universal critical dynamics into an experimentally testable discipline. He predicted that the density of defects after crossing a continuous phase transition in a condensed matter system scales as a universal power law with the quench rate, where the power-law exponent is given by the equilibrium critical exponents and the dimensionality of the system. To this date, the Kibble-Zurek mechanism remains the predilect paradigm to account for the dynamics of a continuous phase transition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last three decades have deeply sharpened our understanding of the universal dynamics and broken symmetries. Yet, two recent thorough reviews written by Kibble, Zurek and one of us (AdC) pointed out that a conclusive experimental test remains elusive to this date [J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 25, 404210 (2013), Int. J. Mod. Phys. A 29, 1430018 (2014)]. This uneasy state of affairs can be understood after appreciating the formidable challenges and requisites involved in experimental studies: exquisite control of the system parameters over a large range of values to test the power-law behavior of the density of defects, knowledge of the correlation length and dynamic critical exponents, clean and large samples without relevant disorder, inhomogeneity or finite-size effects, reliable measurement of topological defects, etc.&lt;br/&gt;
Remarkably enough, and with no exception, previous experimental studies are either restricted to the classical regime [Nat. Phys. 9, 656&amp;ndash;660 (2013), Nat. Commun. 4, 2291 (2013)], or none firm supporting of the KZ theory in quantum regime is given [PRL 106 235304 (2011)], PRL 107, 140402 (2011)]. The prospects for experimental tests in quantum systems are shadowed by the additional requirement of ground state cooling that appears as an insurmountable obstacle with current quantum technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this work,  we embrace Feynman&amp;rsquo;s idea of quantum simulation to experimentally test the universal critical dynamics of a quantum spin chain using a trapped ion in momentum space. This allows us to study the universal dynamics of a clean, homogenous, large sample initialized in its quantum ground state. We focus on the paradigmatic transverse field Ising chain, the cornerstone to understand quantum phase transitions.  We report the experimental evidence of universal scaling of the density of excitations after crossing at a finite rate the quantum critical point of the paramagnetic-ferromagnetic phase transition. The accurate measurement of the resulting density of excitations allows us to experimentally verify the applicability of the Kibble-Zurek mechanism in the quantum regime.  &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Hybrid Quantum network in LQCC</title><link href="http://lqcc.ustc.edu.cn/qng/hybrid-quantum-network-in-lqcc.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-19T10:20:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-09-19T10:20:00+08:00</updated><author><name>qng</name></author><id>tag:lqcc.ustc.edu.cn,2016-09-19:/qng/hybrid-quantum-network-in-lqcc.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The realization of quantum networks composed of quantum nodes and quantum channels is of great importance to the distributed quantum computation and quantum communication. The function of the quantum node is the operation and storage of the quantum state, and the function of the quantum channel is the distribution of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The realization of quantum networks composed of quantum nodes and quantum channels is of great importance to the distributed quantum computation and quantum communication. The function of the quantum node is the operation and storage of the quantum state, and the function of the quantum channel is the distribution of quantum information [1]. Shown in Fig.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure full" style="max-width: 200px; min-width: 7em;"&gt;
&lt;img alt="[Image: Scheme for quantum network by kimble]" border="1" src="./images/research/kimble.PNG" style="max-width: 300px; max-height: 326px;" title="Fig.1."/&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Fig.1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much experimental progress has been achieved in this aspect for different physical systems, such as atomic ensembles, single atoms and trapped ions [2,3,4]. In comparison, hybrid quantum networks consisting of various physical systems [5] can combine the different advantages of diverse physical systems. 
In our group, we try to build a hybrid quantum network combined with trapped ion and rare-earth doped solid state quantum memory. Shown in Fig.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure full" style="max-width: 400px; min-width: 5.5em;"&gt;
&lt;img ]"="" alt="[Image. Hybrid Quantum Network" border="1" src="./images/research/hybrid.PNG" style="max-width: 400px; max-height: 310px;" title="Hybrid Quantum Network"/&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Fig.2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the computing nodes, trapped ions can be a suitable candidate because they are one of the most promising physical systems for the realization of quantum computation and simulation [6, 7].
For the storing nodes, a promising candidate is the rare-earth ion-doped crystal system, because it has already shown excellent merits in regard to quantum memory [8,9,10]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, photonic interface compatible with the physical systems in hybrid quantum network are not identical. Considering the functions and aims, there are some requirements to get a well-fitted photonic interface. The central frequency and bandwidth of the photons should be matched perfectly with the physical systems in hybrid quantum network.Last but not least, entanglement should be existed in this progress. To satisfy the requirements, generation of nondegenerate narrow-band entangled photon pairs will be a good proposal to reach the goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure full" style="max-width: 400px; min-width: 5.5em;"&gt;
&lt;img ]"="" alt="[Image. Hybrid Quantum Network" border="1" src="./images/research/source.PNG" style="max-width: 400px; max-height: 310px;" title="Hybrid Quantum Network"/&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Fig.3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As shown in Fig.3. We came up with a newly-designed conjoined double-cavity structure to generate the nondegenerate entangled narrow-band photon pairs firstly in experiment. By tomography, we get a source with fidelity of xx%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[1] H. J. Kimble, The quantum internet, Nature (London)453, 1023 (2008).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[2] N. Sangouard, &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;, Rev. Mod. Phys. 83, 33 (2011).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[3] S. Ritter, &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;, An elementary quantum network of single atomsin optical cavities, Nature (London)        484, 195 (2012).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[4] L.-M. Duan and C. Monroe, Quantum networks withtrapped ions, Rev. Mod. Phys. 82, 1209 (2010).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[5] M. Wallquist, &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;, Hybrid quantum devices and quantum engineering,Phys. Scr. T137, 014001 (2009).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[6] R. Blatt, D. Wineland, Entangled states of trappedatomic ions, Nature (London) 453, 1008 (2008).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[7] J.-M. Cui, &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;, Supporting Kibble-Zurek Mechanismin Quantum Ising Model through a Trapped Ion, arXiv:1505. 05734.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[8] Z.-Q. Zhou, &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;, Realization of Reliable Solid-State Quantum Memoryfor Photonic Polarization Qubit, Phys. Rev. Lett.108, 190505 (2012).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[9] Z.-Q. Zhou, &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;, Quantum Storage of Three-Dimensional Orbital-Angular-Momentum Entanglementin a Crystal, Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, 070502 (2015).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[10] Jian-Shun Tang, &lt;em&gt;et al&lt;/em&gt;, Nature communications 6, 8652&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Quantum network based cavity QED</title><link href="http://lqcc.ustc.edu.cn/qng/quantum-network-based-cavity-qed.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-19T10:20:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-09-19T10:20:00+08:00</updated><author><name>qng</name></author><id>tag:lqcc.ustc.edu.cn,2016-09-19:/qng/quantum-network-based-cavity-qed.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Progressing along with quantum technologies, scientists are focusing on building quantum network in last decades. Using photons as the flying qubits to link the remote nodes is the key technology in quantum network. Both schemes based on quantum state transfer (between the photons and atoms) and remote entanglement generation (by …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Progressing along with quantum technologies, scientists are focusing on building quantum network in last decades. Using photons as the flying qubits to link the remote nodes is the key technology in quantum network. Both schemes based on quantum state transfer (between the photons and atoms) and remote entanglement generation (by aid of photons) are the solutions. Aiming on the quantum state transfer scheme, which requires strong coupling between single photon and single atom, lots of work have been done including integrating a fiber Fabry&amp;ndash;P&amp;eacute;rot cavity to improve the coupling factor. However there is still a long way to transfer the state of an atom to another atom. On the other hand, although quantum teleportation between ions had been realized basing on entanglement generation scheme, the quite low state preparing rate, which is confined by the photon collection efficiency, limits its application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We plan to use a fiber Fabry&amp;ndash;P&amp;eacute;rot cavity to enhance the collection efficiency of photons, which is based on fluorescence Purcell enhancement with a moderate cooperativity. The cavity is design in the ultraviolet range, which is resonant with dipole transition of Yb ion. The loss of mirror coatings in ultraviolet range is much larger than the coatings in infrared range, the ultraviolet cavity cannot support quantum state transfer scheme well. However, the cavity still have a good cooperativity for florescence enhancement. As the enhanced florescence couple into the cavity mode, the cavity can collect most part fluorescence of the ion when the Purcell enhancement is larger than 1. Utilizing a large core fiber to match the cavity mode and fiber mode, the collected photons can be well coupled in to a single mode fiber. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have made the ultraviolet fiber cavity, the result shows that the cavity supports Purcell enhancement well while keeping a high transmission. Simulations show a single-mode fiber collection efficiency over 50%. This technology can provide ultra-bright single photon sources based on trapped ions, supporting high entanglement generation rate in quantum network.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Welcome for new members</title><link href="http://lqcc.ustc.edu.cn/qng/welcome-for-new-members.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-09-19T10:20:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-09-19T10:20:00+08:00</updated><author><name>qng</name></author><id>tag:lqcc.ustc.edu.cn,2016-09-19:/qng/welcome-for-new-members.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We welcome our new PHD student Zhong-Hua and Ming-Zhong to take part in our group! They both have strong physics background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ZhongHua got his bachelor degress in University of Science and Technology of China (USTC).  &lt;img src="../images/Cavity.png" width="100"/&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MingZhong got his bachelor degress in Shandong University. &lt;img src="../images/Cavity.png" width="100"/&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We welcome our new PHD student Zhong-Hua and Ming-Zhong to take part in our group! They both have strong physics background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ZhongHua got his bachelor degress in University of Science and Technology of China (USTC).  &lt;img src="../images/Cavity.png" width="100"/&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MingZhong got his bachelor degress in Shandong University. &lt;img src="../images/Cavity.png" width="100"/&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>